This task is based on previous CodeWorld tasks.
And these tasks were about some game with levels.
This time we want to write a function
isLessFilledThan that compares different levels.
These levels shall be compared by having a
coordinate range from -10 to 10 for x and y.
We arrange it over this area in order
to check if the levels are the same.
A level is defined as a function from
a pair of integers to an integer.
And this function shall be the isLessFilledThan
function that we have down below here.
But this time there's no type given, so we
have to define the type for this function.
And the isLessFilledThan function shall
be of a type where we compare two levels.
First of all, we can think about having
two arguments, and both are functions.
In fact, functions of this type.
So we have
a function from a pair of integers to an integer and
a function from a pair of integers to an integer.
So let me write this.
Pair of integers and integers to integers.
That's the function of the level –
we have this as our first argument.
And then we have the same
type as our second argument.
Our return type will be Boolean.
Because we just want to return true or
false as a result when comparing those.
We have two arguments which we can define
here in our implementation as well.
So we have level one and level two.
Now we want to compare all those parts and
for this actually, I think, it's
helpful to have a list comprehension.
Because with the list comprehension, we
can range over a whole set of values and
our range is given already.
So I define this locally here
because we want to use it twice.
In order to reuse the code,
we can just define it here.
That's our range and we want to ...
Well, define it here as range.
And we want to use this in
our list comprehension here.
We range over x's and y's; these
are the coordinates of our level.
We want them to just express whether the
field that's at that coordinate
satisfies this description here.
So that, if it's an air tile and in the first
part and in the second value has a pearl, then
we shall return true.
And if both are equal, then
we return true as well.
I think it's helpful to define a
local function for this comparison.
I call it just hasLesser and it compares the
actual field; that's the important thing.
So we can say hasLesser if the first
one is four and the second one is three,
we return true, and in all the
other cases, we compare both values.
And when they are equal, we return true as well.
We can use hasLesser here for
our level one and our level two.
So we compare level one
with level two – well, in fact, at the moment the
types do not match of level one and level two.
For hasLesser, because level one and level two are
functions, but we have to give them pairs actually
in order to get the actual fields, which have
these integer values which we can compare.
That's why I define the tuple or the
point as the coordinate of x and y.
And I give this point to both functions.
Okay, now the actual type of the function
is not correct – of the whole function.
Because I use a list comprehension, but it
returns a list of Booleans in this case,
and we will actually want to have Bool as
the return type, as I specified here earlier.
How can we fix this?
We can say we don't want to have
False as an element of our list.
If False is not an element of our list, then
we are happy with the result of this function.
And I add some code in order to test
if our function does the right thing.
Therefore, I define some very simple levels.
And these are levels which
we can define very basically.
But because I just say they have just one field.
As I define them as levels, they have
type pair of integers to integers.
And the first one is a level which
contains just a single air field.
This air field shall be where x
equals zero and y equals zero.
And an air field has number
four. So this is the air field.
It's written here in the text as well.
Air field has integer code four.
Very importantly, is that we
define the otherwise case.
So if the value does not match zero, so we
are not at point zero here, then we return
zero, which is blank, which
is outside of our field.
Then we define other fields.
Let's say – we have a pearl.
A pearl is three.
And then we have a field for block.
To have another field that we can test.
Let's say this has one.
Now we can write a function test,
which we use in order to just check
that our function is working as expected.
We say that test is working
correctly when air is less filled
than air – this is the
reflexivity that we can test.
That always the x value is the same.
We can say this for air, we can say this
for pearl, and we can say this for block.
– again: for block –
Now I have this file!
I can load it in ghci and run
my tests and they say true.
So, this is actually working.
I call this the reflexivity.
And reflexivity is of type Bool.
We can also test that the
other parts are working.
It shall also be true that
air is less filled than pearl.
Because if we have the same at the same field ...
When we have an air, we have a pearl in the
second one, then our predicate shall be true.
But it shall not be true if
it's the other way around.
Pearl is not less filled than air.
Because if we have a field: If we have
zero there where this pearl is, then...
If at coordinate (0,0) we have a pearl in
the first case but air in the second case,
then that's wrong.
We can check that this test is working as well.
The last part is to check that it's
working for other parts correctly as well.
It shall not be true that block is less filled
than air, and it shall also not be true.
that air is less filled than block.
This is the case as well.
This is just testing, but basically we
can use this function in order to test
that the correct thing is happening here.
Instead of using False notElem here, we
could be a bit smarter here and say that
all the values in the list shall be true,
thus we can use just the and function.
So we can simply write and here and we
can test if the result is still the same.
And that is the case.
There are other implementation
variants possible here.
For instance, you could have written
the hasLesser function differently.
You could have expressed this as
hasLesser x y is x equals 4
and y equals 3 or x equals.
This is the same because we are just having
expressed this not by using pattern-match here,
but by using a Boolean expression
fulfilling both parts here.
So this shall still fulfill the test here.
Of course, if you have a variant of this
it's correct in this example as well.
There are other variants of
expressing this task; for instance, you
could have made it the other way around.
So apply first generating a list
of tuples having the tuples for the
levels and then comparing those.
I write an implementation in order
to show how this could look like.
The idea here is to basically also range over
x and y but just in order to get the field.
I define field here – locally.
field is the actually applied
level function on the coordinates.
But we give this function
as a parameter to field.
That's the basic idea.
Say we do a list comprehension here as well.
We range over x and y and return then
the actual field in the specific level.
Now we have these levels here as well.
We can return the fields, and we can use this
comprehension again to retrieve all those values.
We retrieve these values naming them somehow,
for instance, field one and field two, for the
different fields of level one and level two.
field of level one and field of level 2
We retrieve those by using zip.
We can zip field level 1 and field level 2.
These parts are both lists.
These are the lists of all the fields in the
actual level of the specific range from -10 to 10.
Now we have basically the same
implementation in a different style.
Here using zip and retrieving the fields
first rather than applying the fields
before applying the function.
If we reload that and apply it,
we still get the same result.
There are more possibilities of changing the code
and there are variants of choosing
implementations to your liking.